## **GNANASEKARAN GAJENDIRAN**

DEVOPS ENGINEER - STANDARD CHARTERED, CHENNAI in (





## SUMMARY:

Over 8+ years IT experience in DevOps and Software Engineer in mission critical environments across the Banking industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem-solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, and automation, continuous deployment (CICD) pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

Able to communicate effectively at all levels and able to work on own initiative or within a larger group including during crisis situations.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

DevOps Ansible, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx, Liquibase

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeats, Metricbeat

Monitoring/Log SYSDIG, ITRS, SITESCOPE, MONIT
Programming Shell Scripting, Groovy, Gradle, Python

RDBMS Oracle, MySQL.

OS Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu.

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform.

Certifications RHCE, Ansible, ElasticSearch

**EXPERIENCE:** 

StandardCharteredAutomated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline.Devops EngineerImplemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic Stack.

Chennai Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution. (Jul2014-Present) Introduced Nginx as Gateway & Dockerized it with F5 as load Balancer.

Architecture with spring config server for dynamic variable substitution in ansible.

Infosys Private Ltd Responsible for High availability of Non-Production Environments.

Technology Analyst Written Monitoring Scripts and Configured in SiteScope to alert services/MQ status.

Chennai Troubleshooting on Network, SAN, DNS, LDAP, DB and OS Levels.

(Mar2013-Jun2014) Developed Java based Tool to fetch application properties from several servers.

Administering SiteScope and BladeLogic.

**HCL Technologies** Implemented Single Click Deployment by using ControlTier.

Software Engineer Automated ControlTier Tool Installation, Configuration and Jobs Creations.

Chennai Conducting knowledge transitions cross Support and Dev Teams.

(Dec2009-Feb2013) Implemented ACLS with SUDOERS.

**EDUCATION:** 

BE Anna University

Jun 2005 – Jun 2009 Electronics and Communications Engineering

High School Tamil Nadu, State Board

Jul 2002 – May 2005 Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry and Biology

MORE ABOUT ME:

Awards & Honours Promoted as Devops Engineer from StandardChartered Bank

Rewarded Best Performer Award (INSTA Award) and Buddy Award from Infosys

Honoured Best Performer Award (Live Wire Award) two times from HCL.

INTERESTS AWS, Kubernetes, Sysdig and Prometheus

Python, Gradle and Groovy

HOBBIES DEVOPS, Playing with My Kids, Spending Time with My Families, Shopping

DOB 21-04-1987